下は　どうだった？
How was the lower level?
Everyone was annihilated except for us.
俺たち以外　全滅だよ。
まだ　サスケの部下が
２人　いるそうだ。
It seems like two of Sasuke's subordinates
are still around here.
そいつを　見なかったか？
Did you see them?
We haven't seen them.
見てないな。
They probably died too.
そいつらも
死んだんじゃないか？
Everything is a mess down there.
下は　もう　むちゃくちゃだよ。
No. A Sensory-Type Ninja
from the Hidden Cloud
（オキスケ）いや　雲隠れの感知能力者が
その２人の生存を確認し→
confirmed that they survived.
They asked us to capture them
and then they left.
我々に　拘束するように頼んで
去っていった。
そ…　そうなんですか。
Oh, is that so?
お前たち…→
You two…
鎧を脱げ。
Remove your armor.
Oh my, it seems we've been found out.
あらら…　バレてたみたい。
（重吾）やはり
あまり　いい案ではなかったな。
Just as I thought,
that wasn't a very good plan.
《ナルト：サクラちゃん…→
Sakura, why did you do
something like that?
なんで　あんなことを…》
サイ。　お前　なんで…。
Sai! What are you doing here?
（カカシ）分身だな。
It's a clone.
（サイ）さっき　サクラが→
I'm going to tell you
what Sakura really wanted to say earlier,
but couldn't.
君に　言おうとして言えなかった
本当のことを言うよ。
本当のこと？
"Really wanted to say"?
ふ～む。
（ヤマト）どういうことだ？　サイ。
What do you mean, Sai?
サクラは　告白しにきたわけじゃない。
Sakura didn't come to
confess her love for you.
木ノ葉の同期メンバーで決めた
あることを言いにきた。
The Hidden Leaf Ninja have
come to a consensus
and I'm here to inform you.
おかしいとは思ってたけど
やっぱ　何か隠してたんだな。
I thought it was strange.
So she was hiding something after all.
♪～
君に言えなかった
サクラの気持も…→
I've come to understand her feelings.
今の僕なら　わかるよ。
Why Sakura couldn't bring
herself to tell you.
サイ　教えてくれ。
あることって…。
Tell me, Sai…
about the consensus.
サスケを　木ノ葉の手で処理する。
The Hidden Leaf will deal with Sasuke.
君の　同期メンバー全員が
そのつもりで動く。
Every one of your comrades is committed
to that and will act accordingly.
As One's Friend
サスケを　木ノ葉の手で処理する。
The Hidden Leaf will deal with Sasuke.
君の　同期メンバー全員が
そのつもりで動く。
Every one of your comrades is committed
to that and will act accordingly.
サクラちゃんが…→
Did Sakura…
Did Sakura really agree to that?!
本当に　サクラちゃんが
そんなこと　納得したのか！
Sakura loves Sasuke so much!
サクラちゃんは
サスケのことが　大好きなんだぞ！
なのに…　そんなこと…。
And yet…
How could she?!
今回
木ノ葉を襲った　暁の一件で→
After Akatsuki's attack on our village,
木ノ葉の忍たちは→
the Hidden Leaf Ninja can no longer
recognize Sasuke as one of their own,
暁に協力しているサスケを
容認できなくなった。
not after he supported the Akatsuki.
サクラは　バカじゃないし→
Sakura is not a fool.
それぞれの立場や状況が
わからないほど　子供じゃないさ。
She's not a child who wouldn't understand
the difficulty of the situation.
だから君に
どうにか　そのことを伝えようと→
That's why we came here in person
to try to explain it to you.
ここまで　会いにきたんだ。
くっ…。
だったら…　何で俺に→
Then why didn't she just come out
and tell me the truth?
本当のことを
言ってくれなかったんだ！
簡単には　言えないだろうよ。
It wasn't that simple.
You know that.
お前を苦しめることになるのは
わかってる。
She understood how hurt
you would feel.
だからって…。
But still…
サクラは　サスケを　あきらめ
君が好きだと告白することで→
By telling you
she's given up on Sasuke
and declaring her love for you,
君との約束の重荷を解いた。
she was freeing you from the burden
of that promise you made.
((サクラ：ナルト…　私の　一生のお願い！
Naruto, this is a once
in a lifetime request.
(サスケ君を…　サスケ君を連れ戻して！))
Please…bring Sasuke back!
それでも　君は
サスケを助けたいと言った。
And still, you insisted
on rescuing Sasuke.
だから　本当のことを
言えなかったんだと思う。
I believe that's why
she couldn't tell you the truth.
君の気持を考えたからだよ。
Because she was thinking
about your feelings.
In fact, she probably expected you
to say that.
それに　君がそう言うことも
おそらく　わかってたんだ。
君に本当のことを言うのは→
To be honest, Sakura made us promise
not to tell you the truth.
実は　サクラに
口止めされてたんだ。
自分が
どうにか伝えるって言ってね。
She said she would tell you somehow.
それが　自分の役目だと言ってた。
She said it was her duty to do so.
しかし　ナルトのリアクションが
わかってたなら→
But if she was expecting
Naruto's reaction,
はなから　本当のことを言う
つもりはなかったってことだろ。
she never intended to
tell him the truth, right?
サクラは　どうするつもりだ？
What is Sakura planning to do?
ここからは　僕の想像ですが→
This is just an assumption on my part.
おそらく　サクラは…。
But I believe Sakura…
一人で　サスケを殺すつもりだな。
She intends to kill Sasuke herself.
そうなのか？　サイ！
Is that true, Sai?!
おそらく。
Probably.
((一人で　いろいろ
抱え込まないでください。
Please don't take it all on yourself.
僕も　同じ第七班です。
I feel the same way as you.
それに　みんなも…。
うん。
So does everyone else.
Oh…yeah.
ありがとう　サイ。
Thank you, Sai.
(私も　そのつもりだから))
I know.
サクラは笑って　みんなと協力すると
言ってましたが→
Sakura smiled and told everyone
she would cooperate.
それが作り笑いだと
今度は見抜けましたから。
But this time,
I saw through her fake smile.
ウソだ…
サクラちゃんが　そんなことを。
No way.
Sakura wouldn't do such a thing.
She's crazy about Sasuke—
サクラちゃんは　サスケのことが
あんなに…。
大好きだからこそ
このまま悪へ突き進むサスケを→
It's because she loves him so much
that she can't bear to watch
Sasuke turn more and more evil.
放ってはおけないんだと思う。
大好きだからこそ　そのサスケを
悪の道から救いたいと思ってる。
It's because she loves him so much
that she wants to save Sasuke
from this path of evil.
その方法が
大好きな人を自分の手で→
Even if that means killing the one
she loves with her own hands.
殺めなければならないことに
なるとしても→
それが　サスケを好きになった
彼女なりの覚悟なんだと思う。
That is how committed she is
to her love for Sasuke.
そして　そのことで　ナルト…。
And in doing so, Naruto…
君に恨まれる覚悟もしている。
She's prepared to accept your hatred.
それが　君に一生の重荷を
背負わせようとした→
It's her way of atoning for
the lifelong burden she placed on you.
償いでもあると思っているんだよ。
サクラは　今まで君に頼りすぎた。
Until now, Sakura relied on you too much.
だから今度は　自分一人で
すべてをやろうとしている。
This time, she intends to resolve
everything alone.
サイ…　なんで
俺に　それを話してくれた？
Sai…
Why are you telling me all this?
((サイ：ナルトを苦しめてるのは
サスケだけど→
Sasuke is the source of Naruto's agony.
(君もなんじゃないのかい？))
But aren't you a part of it too?
僕の意でなかったとはいえ
そうサクラを仕向けてしまったのは→
It wasn't my intention,
but I'm partly to blame for
provoking Sakura.
僕のせいでもあるから。
だから　君に言ってしまった。
That's why I told you.
サクラを放っておけなかったし…
僕は　第七班のひとりだから。
I couldn't ignore what Sakura's doing.
And besides, I belong to Team 7.
そうか…。
I see.
《このことを知った
ナルトの胸中は　ゴチャゴチャだな。
Having learned all this,
Naruto must be in turmoil.
さて　どうしたものか》
Now then… What to do?
（テマリ）お前たちに　すぐに
聞いてもらわなければ→
There is something
you must hear immediately.
ならないことがある。
五影会談で何があったか→
We will tell you everything that happened
at the Five Kage Summit.
すべて話す。
（マダラ）久しぶりだな　ダンゾウ。
It's been a long time, Danzo.
うちはの事件以来だな。
We haven't met since
the Uchiha incident.
（ダンゾウ）フー　トルネ…　援護しろ。
Foo, Torune, assist me.
右腕の封を解く。
I'm going to break the seal
on my right arm.
やつを引きつけておくのだ。
Keep him occupied.
やる気だな…　ダンゾウ…。
So you're going for it, Danzo?
マダラ…　やつの能力は未知だ。
Madara… His abilities are limitless.
用心しろ。
（２人）はっ！
Be careful.
– Yes, sir.
（フー）トルネ。　常に
互いを援護しつつ　攻める。
Torune, we'll back each other up
and attack.
（トルネ）わかっている。
I know.
《心転身の…》
Mind Transfer…
柱の中へ消えた。
He disappeared into the pillar.
やはり　物体をすり抜ける
能力はあるようだ。
It seems he can slip
through objects after all.
それで　どうだ？
Well? Are you able to sense his chakra?
今のやつのチャクラは
感知できてるか？
いや…　完全に消えている。
No. He has completely disappeared.
感知と心転身の術…。
A Sensory-Type with Mind Transfer skills.
山中一族の者か。
A member of the Yamanaka Clan, huh?
身を守るために　相手の攻撃を
すり抜けさせるときは→
In order to protect himself,
he de-materializes his body
at the moment of an attack
やつの体すべてが
実体をなくすようだな。
and passes right through it.
攻撃のために
物理的接触をもつときは→
But he solidifies his body to make
physical contact when he attacks.
実体化する。
つまり　カウンターを狙えばいい。
We have to aim for the counterattack.
よく理解した。　いい分析だ。
That was a well thought out analysis.
カウンターのタイミングを意図的に作る。
The counterattack must
be timed perfectly.
俺たちの攻撃を
連続で仕掛け→
We'll attack one after the other
and get him on the second stage.
２段階で行う。
１段目は　囮役だ。
The first stage will be a diversion.
囮役は俺がやる…。
I'll be the decoy.
心転身の術は読まれているしな。
He's already seen through
my Mind Transfer Jutsu.
お前の術　メインでいく。
わかった。
We'll go with your jutsu.
Got it.
《あの手…》
That technique…
トルネ…　あの術を…。
Torune… That jutsu…
Now!
《ここだ！》
こいつ…
攻撃するフリをして　わざと…。
This guy…
He just pretended to attack.
Damn it. We fell for it!
くそ…　引っかけられた…。
Hmm…
ほぅ…　チャクラを流し込んで→
A jutsu to flush in chakra
and destroy cells?
細胞を破壊する術か…
厄介だな。
How troublesome.
すまない　フー…
すぐに取り除く。
Forgive me, Foo.
I'll extract them right away.
チャクラじゃないな…。
This isn't chakra.
These are nano-sized venom beetles.
（マダラ）これは　ナノサイズの毒蟲…。
細菌に近いな。
They are almost like bacteria.
触れると瞬時に
細胞を侵食していく蟲…。
Insects that devour cells on contact.
フッ…　聞いたことがある。
I've heard of them.
お前　油女一族の中でも
秘伝忍術を持つ忍だな。
You are a ninja from the Aburame Clan
who knows Hidden Ninjutsu.
そうか　その蟲の抗体を持つ
油女シクロのガキか。
I see. You're the son
of Shikuro Aburame,
the one with immunity to those insects.
To think you were in the Foundation.
根にいたとはな。
ダンゾウ　いい部下を揃えたな。
Danzo!
You have yourself a good subordinate.
トルネ　すまない。
フー　気を抜くな。
Forgive me, Torune.
Don't blame yourself, Foo.
Use your sensors to
locate him quickly.
すぐにやつの出所を感知しろ。
次でケリをつける。
I'll get him the next time.
Damn it!
クソッ！
He sucked in Torune!
《トルネごと吸い込んだだと！？》
My right arm has been injected
with the venom beetles.
右腕が毒蟲に感染してしまったな。
次は　お前だ！
You're next.
I see.
そうか　そこまで
荒れた会談になったとはね。
Who would have thought the meeting
would become so intense.
やはり　ダンゾウでは…。
I guess with Danzo…
俺は火影ってのは
あまり乗り気じゃないんだけどさ。
I'm not too eager about
becoming the Hokage.
And even if the situation
requires me to accept…
状況がこれじゃあ
仕方ないとしても…。
木ノ葉に帰って　みんなの意見を
聞かないことには→
I'll have to return to
Hidden Leaf Village first
and hear what the others say.
話にならないよ。
マダラが戦争を仕掛けてくるって
宣言してんだぞ。
Madara has declared war on us!
There's no time to deliberate.
悠長なこと言ってられないだろ。
おそらく　みんなの同意は
すぐに得られると思います。
I'm sure everyone will approve.
カカシ先輩が火影ってことで→
We should have them proceed
on the premise
that you are the Hokage, Kakashi.
話を進めておいてもらいましょう。
対応が遅くなって
暁やマダラに先手を打たれ→
If our response is delayed
and the Akatsuki and Madara
take the advantage,
後手に回ってしまうほうが
やばいですから。
that would be even worse.
まぁ　そうなるか　どうも。
I guess you're right. Thanks.
And Sasuke…
それとサスケですね。
ふぅ　会談まで
襲撃するようになるとは…。
For him to attack the summit…
（我愛羅）ナルト　言っておくが
これは八尾と九尾。
Naruto, this is a battle to protect
the Eight-Tails and the Nine-Tails.
つまり　お前を守る戦争でもある。
Namely you.
そして忍の世界のため→
And it's also for the ninja world.
風影として
俺は命がけでお前を守る。
As the Kazekage,
I would give my life to protect you.
If Sasuke Uchiha confronts
暁の配下として→
うちはサスケが俺たち忍連合の前に
立ちはだかるなら→
the Allied Shinobi Forces
as a member of the Akatsuki,
I will show no mercy.
容赦はしない。
((サスケ　お前は俺と似ている。
Sasuke, you and I are alike.
この世の闇を歩いてきた者。
We've both walked through
the darkness of this world.
だからこそ　小さな光明ですら
目に届くはずだ。
That's why you should be able to see
even the faintest glimmer of light.
昔も　そして今も…。
In the past and even now.
（サスケ）俺は　とっくに目を閉じた。
I closed my eyes long ago.
My goals exist only in the darkness.
(俺の目的は闇の中にしかない))
サスケは
お前を見ようとはしていない。
Sasuke doesn't care about you.
All he wants is darkness.
自ら闇を求めている。
ナルト。
Naruto, you told me,
"I am going to be the Hokage."
お前は俺に
自分は火影になる男だと言ったな。
俺は風影になった。
I have become the Kazekage.
影の名を
背負う覚悟を決めたなら→
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
サスケの友として　お前が
本当にやるべきことをやれ。
then do what is right
as Sasuke's friend.
伝えることは
すべて伝えた。
We've said everything we needed to say.
帰るぞ　我愛羅。
Let's go, Gaara.
We will return to our village.
では　これで
私らは　里へ帰る。
はたけカカシ　あなたが
火影になるものとして砂は動く。
Kakashi Hatake…
With the understanding that
you will be Hokage,
the Sand will take action.
（テマリ）同盟国として
情報の混乱がないよう願う。
As allied nations,
I pray that there will be
no conflicting intel between us.
了解した。
Understood.
俺は　お前を友だと思っている。
I consider you my friend.
かつての俺にとって
友とは　ただの言葉。
In the past,
"friend" was merely a word to me.
それ以上でも
それ以下でもなかった。
だが　お前と会って
気づかされた。
大切なのは
その言葉の意味だと。
その意味するところが
なんなのか→
お前は　サスケのために
何をしてやれるのか。
よく考えろ。
行くぞ。
ナルト…。
自分で答えを
出すしかないよ。
（香燐）こんな暗いところで
サスケと２人…。
ムラムラを抑えて
あんたの面倒　見てやってんだ。
いいかげん　回復しやがれ。
ヒッ！　大丈夫なのかよ？
サスケ。
《また　冷たく
変わりゃしないだろうな…》
《でも　やっぱり…》
ここから出せ。
そう慌てるな。
今　ここから出してやる。
外には　お前への土産もある。
うちはサスケか…。
お前は　さがっていろ。
巻き込まれれば死ぬぞ。
ちょうどいい…。
サスケ　マダラ。
お前たちの写輪眼も
いただくとしよう。
＜今日から７代目＞
＜季節のご飯が大好きな豆助＞
≫はーい　おまたせ
できたわよ
＜　それは魚の王様・鯛のうまみが→